so today we're gonna to see something
new which is editing I was not able to
get this one done in a single take so in
addition to my ordinary low audio
quality and I suppose also my relatively
low video quality we're gonna get a
chance to see we try my hand at editing
which I'm imagine also could be
relatively poor so let's just let's say
that earnestness and low five perhaps
equates to integrity and we see the
production value suddenly skyrocket i I
hope you have the appropriate level of
cynicism alright so on to the content
but I wanted us I want to talk about I
think three things all of which are
roughly bucketed under the notion of the
the operating methodology of the city of
how is this thing going to happen and
the three things broadly speaking are
its fundamental design for emergence the
the nature of the team who and the
question of how does it enter into
relationship with the rest of the world
the outside world or at least one aspect
of that relationship
alright so bucket number one the the
fundamental operating methodology
designing for emergence so you know we
know we're dealing with something which
which must fundamentally be autopoietic
we cannot now even meaningfully hope to
design it and this is not that kind of
an object you cannot be a complicated
system it has to be intrinsically
complex which means it needs to
intrinsically become and with is many
ways going to be quite surprising so
let's use the metaphor of the developing
embryo okay way to get to an embryo you
need a couple of core ingredients first
you need an egg second you need a sperm
this egg in the sperm have to come
together in the right way that the DNA
has to has to merge and has to provide
the right kind of framework to steward
the autopoietic process of bringing
nutrients into now I developed an
organism then then you have to have the
ability to take that that a which is now
potent and embed it into into a room and
into a context that can provide it with
those nutrients
to then allow how to put a process to
actually to go into the world by the way
that wound will also need to be embedded
into the context of a mother who can be
in a relationship with the larger world
and bring those resources into the womb
which then brings it into the zygote
which eventually becomes an embryo okay
so that's the that's the metaphor and
that's the thing all right so the idea
behind psyllium is to say okay do we
have the right DNA do we have the right
design criteria do we have the right
decode and do we really understand where
the necessary ingredients the necessary
and sufficient conditions to begin the
process to enable this thing to go
forward and then when we talk about say
for example the the womb I think largely
this is going to be the who the people
who come in the capacity that they bring
the resources that they bring the
history that they bring and and and the
space that they establish to actually
allow in and among themselves and and in
the larger world that is now I think
going to be contemplating this question
the emergent possibility obsidium was a
lot of failure a lot of failing is going
to happen and can they weather that
storm and grow into it and then kids
other groups come in and so the the
people in some sense are simultaneously
the the core nutrient you know as people
are attracted into this and then bring
their capacity they increase the
capacity of the whole to become what it
is and also are in some sense the the
context that are to create the space for
it to be able to to develop and then and
then we actually finally in in some
fundamental sense have the relationship
with the outside world all right so
let's let's talk about those two
components the WHO and particular some
of the characteristics are some of the
sensibility of the zeitgeist of the the
initial who the node 0 cohort and then
also how does this thing come into
relationship with larger world the the
people who are in fact forming the city
mean beginnings node 0 was what I'm
calling it will obviously have to be
coming in extremely mindful of this of
this reality alright so this is a this
is a startup mindset the notion is is
not
for example to create an intentional
community which has a certain
insularity to it right the idea is not
to to go to coach Reiki and sort of hang
out with each other for a couple of
decades and hope things are cool the
intent is to create something that
ultimately at the end of the are
effectively everybody on the planet has
chosen to participate in so it has a lot
of that five - it's a vibe of creation
it's a vibe of innovation right it's a
vibe of working really hard with the
essence of note zero to be
simultaneously
living 'no Slyke human again and also
the exploration of how the autopoietic
process of sodium can be furthered
maximally so it's that kind of a
sensibility so think of it a little bit
like a Mars expedition right the startup
crew of note zero is going to have to
come with a lot of mojo and a lot of
commitment to doing to building
something to building something that is
hard to build and with a lot of novelty
a lot of exploration in what Canon can't
be done then the the last characteristic
which i think is rather important is we
talked about the notion of the
requirement of the sieve 'i'm having a
relationship with this exterior which
you say the rest of the world and the
necessity certainly the beginning in
probably for quite some long period of
time maybe even generations of being
able to pull resources from the outside
world into this idiom well you might
think of that it's sort of like a
balance of trade it was the way a
nation-state operates and if the well
this doesn't necessarily work that much
these days but caught a decade ago or as
it's called four decades ago if the
united states wanted to import cars from
japan then the united states needed to
have something that it was providing to
japan maybe food right so we gave them
food they gave us cars the balance of
trade was roughly even in you're good to
go
certainly that can I can be pretty
confident that's idioms going to have to
something in the direction of an even
balance of trade so what's that look
like
well it is my my sense that it what it
looks like is
the the psyllium should be the most
generative location it should be a place
where the the synergy value of of
creative collaboration of what happens
you bring human beings together to
collaborate with each other is at a
high-water mark bad better than the best
wood exists in the world today so places
like saying you know Google which
notoriously has very high creativity and
very high talented people would be the
standard and that this idiom should be
more generative and so areas where that
kind of collaborative creativity has
value like the cutting edge of science
and technology is places where the
Citians should have sustainable
competitive advantage it should simply
out-compete everybody else and I don't
necessarily mean that the no zero are
you talking about a hundred fifty people
isn't going to out-compete Google across
all dimensions but as more and more
people enter into the mesh the mesh
shouldn't fact relatively quickly begin
to grab hold territories of creative
endeavor particularly the virtual domain
and be decisively out competitive and
this is important because that's a lot
of the future a lot of the things that
matter in the future economy any
possible future economy are of that sort
right things that have to do with like
artificial intelligence and virtual
reality and you know cutting edge new
technologies around energy and waste
disposal and you know fill in the blank
that kind of thing should be the bread
and butter that should be what's idiom
does better than anyone else and
therefore provides the basis for its
balance of trade with the outside world
so keep that in mind we're not an even
vaguely talking about a an eco village
that tries to trade you know organic
artichokes or a hippie commune that
tries to trade handmade woven baskets
with the rest of the world quite quite
the opposite actually the intent of this
idiom is that it's trading the most
valuable things and is able to outcome
heat the rest of the world in providing
those most valuable things by its very
nature by its design